Guide to the Leo Bogart Papers, 1912-2010 and undated RL.10146
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Audiovisual Materials, 1972-2004 and undated, 1 boxes
  - Original recordings (CLOSED)
    - Computer files
      - Freedom Forum Russia workshop
        - OR35. Designing Good Ads by Bill Solch, 1992. Format: floppy disk (90mm) (Box 98)
        - OR36. I.B.M. disk, 1992. Format: floppy disk (90mm) (Box 98)
        - OR37. Buying Services and the Media Marketplace speech slides, São Paulo, Brazil, 1998 Apr. 15. Format: floppy disk (90mm) (Box 98)
        - OR38. Innovations in Newspaper Marketing speech presentation, 2004 Sept. 15. Format: CD-R (Box 98)
- 2022 Addition, 1921-2010; 1
  Scope and Contents
  Addition contains primarily personal materials relating to Bogart's service during World War II; correspondence with family, spouse Agnes Bogart, and Israel Goldiamond; childhood art and creative writing. There are also materials relating to Brooklyn College when Bogart attended, including material on the anticommunist movement there.
  - Personal and Professional Files, 1921-2008; 1
    - Awards, 1962-2005 (Box 99)
    - Biographical information, 1940-2005 (Box 99)
    - Birth certificate (English and Polish), 1921; 1948 (Box 99)
    - Brooklyn College (includes anticommunism materials), 1938-1940 (Box 99)
    - Brooklyn College--Clippings, 2001 (Box 99)
    - Brooklyn College--Clippings, newsletters, 1938-2001 (Box 103)
    - Brooklyn College--Diploma, 1941 (Box 99)
    - Brooklyn College--Reunions, class of 1941, 1991; 2001 (Box 99)
    - Clippings, 1936-1945 (Box 102)
      Includes materials relating to Abraham Lincoln assassination; Spanish Civil War; Mussolini; Nazi Germany; World War II; Franklin Roosevelt; Harry S Truman
    - Clippings, 1938-2002; 2 folders (Box 103)
    - Correspondence (includes materials relating to military service in World War II), 1937-2002; 5 folders (Box 99)
    - Correspondence--Israel Goldiamond (includes statement from Nazi Gauleiter Alfred Meyer), 1942-1945 (Box 99)
    - Correspondence--Writing and publishing, 1962-2004 (Box 99)
    - Employment, 1976-2001 (Box 99)
    - Erasmus High School, 1935-1936 (Box 99)
    - Joke file, approximately 1967-1997 (Box 99)
    - Memoirs of John Heinig, 1990s (Box 99)
      (1914-2004) Heinig's family fled Germany in the 1930s and eventually settled in the U.S. Heinig served in U.S. military intelligence, as did Bogart, during World War II. After the war Heinig worked in pharmaceutical sales.
    - Memorabilia, 1952-2009 (Box 99)
    - Motivation research, 1947-1956 (Box 99)
    - Newspaper Advertising Bureau, 1988 (Box 99)
    - Notes for a personal archive, approximately 2000 (Box 99)
    - Obituaries, 2005 (Box 99)
    - Obituaries--Others, 1970-2005 (Box 99)
    - Orange Blossom Club (Matchmaking service direct mail), 2000 (Box 101)
      In Election Polls, the News Media, and Democracy, ed. Paul J. Lavrakas and Michael W. Traugott; Chatham House
    - Personal files (includes materials relating to military service in World War II), 1944-2002; 3 folders (Box 99)
    - Philip Pauly--Articles, obituary, 1979-2008 (Box 99)
      (1950-2008) Historian of science; married to Michele Bogart 1981.
    - Photographs, 1940s-2003; 3 folders (Box 99)
    - Portuguese bullfight broadsides, approximately 1964 (Box 101)
    - Retirement, 1985-1992 (Box 99)
    - Skteches and cartoons, 1930s (Box 99)
  - Writings and Illustrations, 1932-2010; 2
    - 7A4 and 7B4 EOW Jabber, 1932 (Box 101)
    - 8A1 Forum, 1932 (Box 99)
    - America's Interest in the Comics, 1949 (Box 99)
    - American Newspapers. How They Have Changed and How They Must Keep Changing, 2005 (Box 100)
    - An Itch in Time (Short story), 1930s (Box 99)
    - Animaland Tales--Illustrations, approximately 1934 (Box 99)
    - Animaland Tales--Stories, approximately 1934 (Box 99)
    - Art--Drawings, 1930s (Box 103)
    - Bibliography, 1990s; 2 folders (Box 99)
    - Book contracts, 1990-2001 (Box 101)
    - Book covers (dust jackets), 1976-2003 (Box 103)
    - Columbia University seminar, 1967 (Box 99)
    - Cool Words, Cold War, 1995 (Box 100)
    - Current Controversies in Marketing Research (editor), 1969 (Box 100)
    - El Toro (Bethel Vt.), 1940 (Box 99)
    - Estrategia Publicitaria (Portuguese edition of Strategy in Advertising), 1972 (Box 100)
    - Expect no Substitutes, 1996 (Box 99)
    - Fan Mail for the Philharmonic, 1949 (Box 99)
    - Finding Out, 2003-2004 (Box 99)
    - Fordham Study of the University Press, 2004 (Box 99)
    - Fragments, 1930s-1940 (Box 101)
    - Fragments, 1930s-1940 (Box 103)
    - Freedom to Know or Freedom to Say?, 1993 (Box 99)
    - Fulbright--Algerians in France (French and English), 1952 (Box 99)
    - Gee Whiz (play), 1930s (Box 99)
    - Germany, World War II, 1945 (Box 99)
    - High school, 1938 (Box 99)
    - How I Earned the Ruptured Duck, 2004 (Box 99)
    - How the Moo-Cow Gives Us Milk (short story), 1930s (Box 99)
    - Ivan Dee publishers, 2003-2010 (Box 99)
    - J. Bogart--At Five O'Clock in a Subway, approximately 1930s (Box 99)
    - La Prensa y Su Publico (Spanish edition of Press and Public), 1985 (Box 100)
    - London Courier May 1815, 1930s (Box 101)
    - Mass Media in the Year 2000, 1967 (Box 99)
    - Media and Democracy, 1995 (Box 99)
    - Politics, Polls, and Poltergeists: A Critical View of the 1996 Election, 2000 (Box 100)
    - Polls and the Awareness of Public Opinion second edition, 1985 (Box 100)
    - Review of Ernest Dichter's The Strategy of Desire, 1960 (Box 99)
    - Reviews and notices of Bogart's publications, 1999-2005 (Box 99)
    - Short story draft, 1963 (Box 99)
    - Stories, 1940s-1990s (Box 99)
    - Strategia in Pubblicita (Italian edition of Strategy in Advertising), 1990 (Box 100)
    - Strategy in Advertising, 1967 (Box 100)
    - The Age of Television, 1956 (Box 100)
    - The Age of Television 3rd edition, promotional brochure, 1972 (Box 99)
    - The Marketer as Radical, 1968 (Box 99)
    - Travel memoir (Chad and coastal Africa), 1960s (Box 99)
      Handwritten notes on a trip to Chad and western Africa; includes a brief mention of a chance encounter with linguist Alan S. Kaye.
    - What Does It All Mean?, 1996 (Box 99)